<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blag</title><link href="http://avi.im/blag/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://avi.im/blag/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://avi.im/blag/</id><updated>2015-05-23T18:30:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>An exploit on Gaana.com gave me access to their entire User Database</title><link href="http://avi.im/blag/2015/hacking-gaana/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-23T18:30:00+05:30</updated><author><name>avi</name></author><id>tag:avi.im,2015-05-12:blag/2015/hacking-gaana/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT(28/May/2015)&lt;/strong&gt;: You have probably read about Gaana hack in recent news. But this exploit is different than the one found by &lt;a href="http://www.thegeekbyte.com/4841/gaana-com-database-compromised-by-hackers/"&gt;MakMan and g00n&lt;/a&gt; and was found much earlier. Mak Man's hack includes SQL Injection, but the vulnerability I found could have been exploited by anyone with a browser and internet connection. No expertise required at all, that's what makes this even more ugly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since &lt;a href="http://blog.mclov.in/path-uploads-your-entire-iphone-address-book-to-its-servers-22HGO5EiLJKhWZPKdMOgdw"&gt;Path - iPhone Address Book fiasco&lt;/a&gt; I have developed a habit of doing MITM and checking app's internal APIs. Yesterday I was playing around with &lt;a href="http://gaana.com"&gt;Gaana.com&lt;/a&gt;'s &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/gaana-unlimited-bollywood/id585270521?mt=8"&gt;app&lt;/a&gt;, I came across this vulnerability. Gaana was started by The Times Group, the same guys behind the national daily newspaper The Times Of India. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came across an internal API which gave me access to their entire user database (more than 11 Million records). Surprisingly, it did not require any cookies, authentication, session id or anything. Anyone with an URL would have had access to Gaana's User DB. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got access to following data of each user:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Profile picture &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email address &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date of birth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last song they listened on Gaana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="all the poor users" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/all-users-censored.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following image shows my personal info on Gaana.com which was accessible to anyone:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="this is me" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/me.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, here's &lt;a href="https://archive.is/HEvUv"&gt;proof&lt;/a&gt;. If &lt;s&gt;Archive Today&lt;/s&gt; &lt;a href="http://archive.is"&gt;Archive Is&lt;/a&gt; can access the data then anyone can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Times Internet CEO Satyan Gajwani's user id on Gaana user database is &lt;code&gt;72&lt;/code&gt; and the last song he listened on Gaana was &lt;em&gt;Happy Birthday&lt;/em&gt; from album &lt;em&gt;Party Time Songs And Nursery Rhymes&lt;/em&gt;. The current Gaana's business head, Pawan Agarwal's user id is &lt;code&gt;831&lt;/code&gt; and the last song he listened on Gaana was &lt;em&gt;Hangover&lt;/em&gt; from movie &lt;em&gt;Kick&lt;/em&gt;. Avinash Mudaliar, the co-founder and former head of Gaana's user id is &lt;code&gt;57&lt;/code&gt;. And The last song he listened on Gaana was &lt;em&gt;Khuda Bhi&lt;/em&gt; from movie &lt;em&gt;Ek Paheli Leela&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I had access to the all the users of Gaana. &lt;strong&gt;Before I got bored, the last record I checked was 11,872,026 (11 Million something) user&lt;/strong&gt;. However not all of data was filled, some profiles were deleted and some had null values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got an idea about how they are handling user account deletion. Spoiler alert, even if they have deleted your account, they still retain your profile picture. However I have no idea how do I delete my account. I couldn't find any such option in the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Hack&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During normal session, I came across an API which was retrieving user data from Gaana's database:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;api.gaana.com/user.php?type=get_user_object&amp;amp;&amp;amp;user_id=&amp;lt;user_id&amp;gt;&amp;amp;token=&amp;lt;token&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;above API requires &lt;code&gt;user_id&lt;/code&gt; of the user whose data needs to be accessed and an authentication &lt;code&gt;token&lt;/code&gt; for this transaction. Now in a well designed app, the user should be able make requests only to his account and not to anyone else's. The token, may be, should linked to the user id, generated every time and should authenticate the request. The unique token per session should give access to the unique user. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The API call to get my info was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;http://api.gaana.com/user.php?type=get_user_object&amp;amp;&amp;amp;user_id=11875135&amp;amp;token=d4f9763714ad89e839605e460ef1b4556
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;My first doubt was, why there is even a &lt;code&gt;user_id&lt;/code&gt; field. I am not an expert developer, but if I were designing I wouldn't include &lt;code&gt;user_id&lt;/code&gt; in the API call. The &lt;code&gt;token&lt;/code&gt; should be just enough. And I would regenerate it for every session or make it expire after few hours or something like that. Or I would use OAuth2. And of course, make this communication over TLS/SSL. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I copied the above URL and opened it in Browser and it showed my info. Without HTTPS. I have never used or logged into Gaana.com in my browser. So I assumed it's not doing any other validation and using only &lt;code&gt;token&lt;/code&gt;. Though not using HTTPS was worrisome. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I incremented my &lt;code&gt;user_id&lt;/code&gt; by 1 and sent GET again. Return response status was 200. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to be really sure. So I created a throwaway profile on Gaana. And yes, &lt;a href="https://archive.is/bkuNY"&gt;I was able to access it with same token&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I kept on changing &lt;code&gt;user_id&lt;/code&gt; and started sending GETs. It always worked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="user1" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/user1.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User 9,99,999:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="user999999" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/user999999.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User 11872026(11 Million something):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="user11872026" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/user11872026.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several hours had already passed, but still my token was active. I logged out of Gaana app, cleared app data, but it was still working. Then I thought, would it work if I change the token? &lt;a href="https://archive.is/lTAIx"&gt;Entered&lt;/a&gt; some gibberish of same length:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="somerandomtoken" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/somerandomtoken.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well yeah, it did work. Then another &lt;a href="https://archive.is/wsGC6"&gt;try&lt;/a&gt;, you know, just to be sure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="somerandomtoken2" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/somerandomtoken2.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm...There's something &lt;a href="https://archive.is/BngCd"&gt;really fishy&lt;/a&gt; was going on. What if I don't provide any &lt;code&gt;token&lt;/code&gt; at all? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="wut" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/wut.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WUT!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So token wasn't required at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All you had to was loop through &lt;code&gt;user_id&lt;/code&gt; starting from 1. Following simple four line Python script was enough to fetch all the details of Gaana users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;requests&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;api&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;http://api.gaana.com/user.php?type=get_user_object&amp;amp;&amp;amp;user_id={0}&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;SOME_NUM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;requests&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;api&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;format&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;())&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It took me ~50 minutes (used &lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/time.html#time.time"&gt;&lt;code&gt;time.time()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) to fetch 10,000 user records:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="frequency" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/frequency.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bonus:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following image shows how user deletion is being done on Gaana. Note that the profile picture was valid, so I guess they retain your profile picture even if you delete your account from Gaana. However I have no idea how to delete my account on Gaana. Most probably, I have to contact them to have my account deleted. (which I should do very very soon.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="a deleted user" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/deleteduser.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A random row with null data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="a null user" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/nulluser.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Script&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Removed the script on request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Aftermath&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the entire chain of events:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the exploit on 12/May/2015, ~3.30 PM. By 4.30 PM, I was convinced that Gaana had a vulnerability. I Googled for their security team email, searched if they have Bug Bounty Programmes. But neither I found any email or Bug Bounty programmes on Gaana. Gaana did not have any 'Contact Us' in their website footer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tweeted them on Twitter and waited for response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gaana"&gt;@gaana&lt;/a&gt; lets say hypothetically some1 hacked ur server &amp;amp; got access. Hw should they go abut contacting ur security team? security@gaana.com?&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; avi (@iavins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/iavins/status/598088551394189312"&gt;May 12, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="http://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were active on Twitter, replying to others. But did not reply to me. May be they thought I was pulling some prank. Also, I did find a contact form on their website after bit of searching(to which they responded after three days).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tweeted again in night:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gaana"&gt;@gaana&lt;/a&gt; guys, can you tell me how do I get in touch with your security/bugs team?&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; avi (@iavins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/iavins/status/598166155736457216"&gt;May 12, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they finally replied to me next day and asked me to DM, which &lt;a href="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/dm.png"&gt;I did&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally their dev emailed on May 13th evening and I sent him all the details, including SQL dump (so that he takes me seriously):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="first email" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/firstemail.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 17th (i.e. 5 days after the exploit), I emailed them again asking why it wasn't fixed yet. Their site was up and running, but exploit wasn't fixed. I was worried if someone else figures this out and makes the data public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their developer called me again and assured me that it will be fixed soon and it's taking time because of API backward compatibility issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometime on May 23-24rd (i.e. ~10 days after exploit) the vulnerability was partially fixed. Now you were able to get full name and profile pic. However API was still openly accessible, over HTTP, in the browser:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="partial fix" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/partialfix.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 28th May, &lt;a href="http://www.thegeekbyte.com/4841/gaana-com-database-compromised-by-hackers/"&gt;MakMan and g00n&lt;/a&gt; found another exploit using SQL injection. And Gaana was down for maintenance for most of the day. In evening, I received a call from Gaana's business head and was assured that it will be fixed asap. I was hoping they will fix it, as it's been already two weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I was wrong. It wasn't &lt;a href="https://archive.is/uuifC"&gt;fixed&lt;/a&gt;. It made me angry and furious because they took SQL injection pretty seriously because it was all over news and hurting their PR. I was thinking, how they would have reacted to this issue, if I had made this whole thing public from beginning. I &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/iavins/status/604150195442475009"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; to Gaana CEO for his email ID, I never received any reply. But then...I found his email from the very database I had hacked and sent another email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 30 2015, evening &lt;a href="https://archive.is/7EaEx"&gt;Gaana&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/gaanadown.png"&gt;was down&lt;/a&gt; again, so was the &lt;a href="https://archive.is/ksPRd"&gt;API end point&lt;/a&gt;. Are they finally fixing the exploit I found? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="api end was down" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/apidown.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 30, 2015, around ~10pm, I checked again. The exploit was finally &lt;a href="https://archive.is/fWEDq"&gt;fixed&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="partial fix" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/apifixed.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaana team took almost 3 weeks to fix the exploit. Would they have treated this exploit differently, if I had made this public since day one? Also, it was not easy for me to reach out to Gaana and it took them a day to reply. It was difficult to find their contact information from their site, I wonder do they even have security team for handling exploits. Usually companies have emails like security@company.com for such things. Gaana mentions no such things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not like Gaana is a new kid in the block, it was launched in 2010 by &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Times_Internet"&gt;Times Internet&lt;/a&gt;, who run the largest websites of India - Times of India, The Economic Times, Indiatimes etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, Gaana is not an exception. A cursory search on Indian companies will tell you that, hardly any companies have such policies. Recent vulnerabilities found on Ola, Freecharge, Zopnow, FoodPanda etc make me more sceptical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions to ponder: Is our private data really safe with Indian startups? Are web/app security practices completely being ignored, to win the race of 'first to be in the market'? Do companies really care about privacy of their users? or only about profits?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="hacking"></category><category term="python"></category></entry><entry><title>Flashing Asus-WRT Merlin by XVortex on NetGear NightHawk R7000</title><link href="http://avi.im/blag/2015/asus-wrt-merlin-on-netgear-r7000/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-10T22:20:00+05:30</updated><author><name>avi</name></author><id>tag:avi.im,2015-05-10:blag/2015/asus-wrt-merlin-on-netgear-r7000/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Note:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to achieve this and in this tutorial I follow two flash method. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Preparation:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This guide assumes you are on stock firmware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are already on DD WRT or Tomato, ignore step 2 of procedure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doesn't matter whether you are on Windows, Linux or Mac. Everything happens in browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you are connected to the router over one of WAN ports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It doesn't matter which firmware version you are currently on. My router came with &lt;code&gt;V1.0.3.XX&lt;/code&gt;, which I later upgraded to &lt;code&gt;V1.0.4.28_1.1.64&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download these two files:&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tomato Initial CHK file (&lt;code&gt;.chk&lt;/code&gt;), which upgrades your NetGear firmware to Tomato - &lt;a href="http://tomato.groov.pl/download/K26ARM/Netgear%20R-series%20initial%20files/tomato-R7000-initial.chk"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XWRT TRX file (&lt;code&gt;.trx&lt;/code&gt;), which upgrades Tomato to XVortex's AsusWRT-Merlin (the thing you finally want). Current latest version is &lt;code&gt;v378.53_0&lt;/code&gt;. The zip file contains &lt;code&gt;.chk&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;.trx&lt;/code&gt; files, you can ignore the &lt;code&gt;.chk&lt;/code&gt; for this guide - &lt;a href="http://mega.co.nz/#!lllgHBpT!oFGLRxwtkXgeijqgvDYRwbKh48gG9yGJLhsQefvJEGI"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Procedure:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login to your router. Reset it to factory settings (&lt;code&gt;Advanced&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Administration&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Backup Settings&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Revert to factory default settings&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flash the &lt;code&gt;.chk&lt;/code&gt; file, after this procedure firmware will be upgraded to Tomato. (&lt;code&gt;Advanced&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Administration&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Router Update&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Browse&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Apply&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now flash the &lt;code&gt;.trx&lt;/code&gt; file which upgrades to XVortex's Firmware. You will see 'successful' message at end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now if your router is not being detected, do manual reboot of the router.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect to the router, if there are any IP conflicts it will be displayed. It should now show you the Installation Wizard. Either follow it or skip it. But it will require you to set the WPA creds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do another reset (&lt;code&gt;Administration&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Restore/Save/Upload Setting&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Factory default&lt;/code&gt; OR &lt;code&gt;http://&amp;lt;router_ip_address&amp;gt;/Advanced_SettingBackup_Content.asp&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat step 4 if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the installation wizard at your wish, same as in step 5.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all!! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Post installation:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To set TX power to 30%-50%, for both bands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;Wireless&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Professional&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Tx power adjustment&lt;/code&gt; (or &lt;code&gt;http://&amp;lt;router_ip_address&amp;gt;/Advanced_WAdvanced_Content.asp&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set &lt;code&gt;Tx power adjustment&lt;/code&gt; to 30% - 50%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change &lt;code&gt;Band&lt;/code&gt; to 5Ghz and do step 2 again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope this helps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Credits:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check &lt;a href="http://www.linksysinfo.org/index.php?threads/asuswrt-merlin-on-netgear-r7000.71108/page-5#post-261251"&gt;this thread&lt;/a&gt; where I originally wrote this tutorial. Thanks to @XVortex for this fine firmware. Thanks to @slidermike who actually introduced me to this, or else I was going to try Tomato. Thanks to @ManiDhillon, @freibooter and @mito for answering my noobie questions and giving me instructions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="r7000"></category><category term="asus-wrt"></category></entry><entry><title>Install Windows 8 UEFI on Legacy BIOS with Clover (and Dual boot with Yosemite)</title><link href="http://avi.im/blag/2014/install-uefi-windows-yosemite-dualboot/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-12-28T16:20:00+05:30</updated><author><name>avi</name></author><id>tag:avi.im,2014-12-28:blag/2014/install-uefi-windows-yosemite-dualboot/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial I am going to explain how to install Windows 8 on a Legacy BIOS in UEFI mode (Yes! It's possible!!) using Clover and dual boot with Yosemite. Technically this tutorial should work for Windows 7 and Mavericks also, but I haven't tried. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial was originally written for Insanely Mac Forums. Check the &lt;a href="http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/topic/303615-guide-install-windows-8-uefi-on-legacy-bios-with-clover-and-dual-boot-with-yosemite/"&gt;original thread&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What you get?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have a machine with Legacy BIOS and at the end of tutorial, you would have Yosemite OS X and Windows 8.1, in UEFI mode, on a GPT  partition with Clover as Bootloader. Isn't that amazing? This tutorial covers installation of both Yosemite and Windows 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why GPT/UEFI?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can have multiple Recovery Partitions in GPT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on BIOS, sometimes Clover doesn't play well in Non-UEFI. You may face all sorts of weird boot/BCD errors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT can support more than 2TB space (MBR cannot)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can have upto 128 partitions (woot!) in GPT (as opposed ONLY 4 primary partitions in MBR/Hybrid MBR partition scheme)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT disk provides greater reliability due to replication and cyclical redundancy check (CRC) protection of the partition table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UEFI enables better use of bigger hard drives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical changes abound in UEFI. UEFI has room for more useful and usable features than could ever be crammed into the BIOS. Among these are cryptography, network authentication, support for extensions stored on non-volatile media, an integrated boot manager, and even a shell environment for running other EFI applications such as diagnostic utilities or flash updates. In addition, both the architecture and the drivers are CPU-independent, which opens the door to a wider variety of processors (including those using the ARM architecture, for example).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT/UEFI is the future ;-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Credits:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big thanks to &lt;a href="http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/user/846696-fusion71au/"&gt;fusion71au&lt;/a&gt;, he guided me and helped me to install UEFI Windows on my laptop and made it possible. In fact, this tutorial is actually combination of several of his posts (check Sources section).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A pendrive of 200MB (or more) for test Clover config (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two pendrives of 8GB (or more), one for OS X and another for Windows installation media. OR a single pen drive of 16GB (or more).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A running OS X machine in real Mac or Hackintosh or as virtual OS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Install OS X Yosemite.app&lt;/code&gt; downloaded and present in &lt;code&gt;Applications&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows 8 ISO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Latest Clover, Clover Configurator, Kext Wizard, Rufus, HFSPlus.efi and FakeSMC.kext (and other kexts based on your machine)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Downloads:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/cloverefiboot/files/latest/download"&gt;Clover&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hackintoshosx.com/files/file/49-clover-configurator/"&gt;Clover Configurator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hackintoshosx.com/files/file/2136-kext-wizard-3-7-10/"&gt;Kext Wizard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://rufus.akeo.ie/"&gt;Rufus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/JrCs/CloverGrowerPro/raw/master/Files/HFSPlus/X64/HFSPlus.efi"&gt;HFSPlus.efi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Test Clover Config (Optional):&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is an optional part and only applies to people who already have a hackintosh running. And also for first time users of Clover. Feel free to skip it if it doesn't apply to you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before installing Yosemite/Clover, it's better to test Clover on currently installed Hackintosh. First, it saves all the trouble of post-installation and second, you will be proceeding to install Yosemite once you have confirmed everything is working properly (and no dirty surprises). For this, you do NOT need to install Clover on your current HDD, it may mess up your current installation. Idea is to install Clover on a different HDD(or a test HDD) and without harming current installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plug in the 200MB (or more) pen drive. Open disk utility, select this drive, under &lt;code&gt;Erase&lt;/code&gt; tab choose &lt;code&gt;Format&lt;/code&gt; as &lt;code&gt;MS-DOS(FAT)&lt;/code&gt; and give name &lt;code&gt;CLOVER&lt;/code&gt;(or whatever you want) and hit &lt;code&gt;Erase&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Erasing test usb" src="http://i.imgur.com/Bc2948b.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;Partition&lt;/code&gt; tab, select &lt;code&gt;1 Partition&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;Partition Layout&lt;/code&gt;, Give name as &lt;code&gt;CLOVER&lt;/code&gt;, format as &lt;code&gt;MS-DOS(FAT)&lt;/code&gt;. Click &lt;code&gt;Options&lt;/code&gt; at the bottom and select &lt;code&gt;Master Boot Record&lt;/code&gt;. Hit &lt;code&gt;Apply&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Partition" src="http://i.imgur.com/sDcdcik.png" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Master Boot Record" src="http://i.imgur.com/9UoOKPK.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your drive is formatted properly now. It can have Clover installed for test USB drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run Clover and change install location to this drive, &lt;code&gt;CLOVER&lt;/code&gt; and customize by selecting &lt;code&gt;Bootloader&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Install boot0ss in MBR&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;CloverEFI&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;CloverEFI 64-bits SATA&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Drivers64UEFI&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;EmuVariableUefi-64&lt;/code&gt;. Perform installation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="install location" src="http://i.imgur.com/cOtGzUY.png" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="boot0ss and SATA" src="http://i.imgur.com/ZPpE5h5.png" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="drivers" src="http://i.imgur.com/Otd8odM.png" /&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clover is installed to the drive. However you need to copy few more files. You will need &lt;code&gt;config.plist&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;DSDT.aml&lt;/code&gt; which are specific to your system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put &lt;code&gt;config.plist&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER&lt;/code&gt; directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put &lt;code&gt;DSDT.aml&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/ACPI/patched&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put &lt;code&gt;HFSPlus.efi&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/drivers64&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/drivers64UEFI&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete &lt;code&gt;VBoxHfs-64.efi&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/drivers64&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/drivers64UEFI&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put &lt;code&gt;FakeSMC.kext&lt;/code&gt; and other kexts required in &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/kexts/10.10&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all and your Clover test drive is ready! Now boot using this USB and boot into your Hackintosh. Make sure everything working and once confirmed, proceed next to installation of Yosemite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Creating Installation Media:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will prepare a single USB drive which can be used to install Yosemite, Windows (and even Ubuntu if you fancy!). We have will format this to GPT, create 2 partitions, one for OS X and another for Windows installation files. This drive needs to be more than 16GB so that it can have all three installation files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erase the USB drive, using Disk Utility. Make 3 partitions for OS X (call it &lt;code&gt;Yosemite&lt;/code&gt;), Windows (call it &lt;code&gt;WIN81&lt;/code&gt;) and Ubuntu. Select OS X Partition as &lt;code&gt;Mac OS Extended Journaled&lt;/code&gt;,  Windows partition as &lt;code&gt;MS-DOS(FAT)&lt;/code&gt; and Ubuntu partition as &lt;code&gt;ext4&lt;/code&gt;. (If you don't want Ubuntu, make only two partitions). Make sure you are giving 7GB (or more) for each OS X and Windows installation partitions. Select ‘GPT (GUID Partition Table)’ under &lt;code&gt;Options&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="partition" src="http://i.imgur.com/BcE2FG5.png" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="GUID" src="http://i.imgur.com/lH2FkxY.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mount Windows 8 installation ISO and copy Windows 8 installation files to this FAT32 Windows Partition, &lt;code&gt;WIN81&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install Clover into the EFI partition of this USB by targeting the &lt;code&gt;OSX&lt;/code&gt; partition and customize by selecting &lt;code&gt;Install Clover in the ESP&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Bootloader&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Install boot0ss in MBR&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;CloverEFI&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;CloverEFI 64-bits SATA&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Drivers64UEFI&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;EmuVariableUefi-64&lt;/code&gt;. Perform installation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Yosemite drive" src="http://i.imgur.com/7p2hE0w.png" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="ESP, boot0ss" src="http://i.imgur.com/7aLwnHZ.png" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="drivers etc" src="http://i.imgur.com/Kk0xNm6.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once clover is installed EFI partition will be mounted automatically. Open it and now you need put few more files. You will need &lt;code&gt;config.plist&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;DSDT.aml&lt;/code&gt; which are specific to your system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put &lt;code&gt;config.plist&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER&lt;/code&gt; directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put &lt;code&gt;DSDT.aml&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/ACPI/patched&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put &lt;code&gt;HFSPlus.efi&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/drivers64&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/drivers64UEFI&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete &lt;code&gt;VBoxHfs-64.efi&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/drivers64&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/drivers64UEFI&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put &lt;code&gt;FakeSMC.kext&lt;/code&gt; and other kexts required in &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/kexts/10.10&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we need to copy Yosemite installation file to USB drive. Make sure &lt;code&gt;/Applications/Install OS X Yosemite.app&lt;/code&gt; exists and run following in terminal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sudo /Applications/Install\ OS\ X\ Yosemite.app/Contents/Resources/createinstallmedia --volume /Volumes/Yosemite --applicationpath /Applications/Install\ OS\ X\ Yosemite.app --no interaction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above command assumes your partition for OS X installation files is named as &lt;code&gt;Yosemite&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your USB installation drive is ready. This can be used to install both Yosemite and Windows 8. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installation of Yosemite:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will create appropriate partitions and install Yosemite. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: The Yosemite Installation section here is very concise and brief. You should actually refer to the thread relevant your machine/laptop. For starters, check &lt;a href="http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/topic/298027-guide-aio-guides-for-hackintosh"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; All In One Guides of Hackintosh. Next, try either &lt;a href="http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/forum/137-osx86-installation/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/forum/213-notebooks/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It'd be better if you post all your Yosemite installation doubts in those threads/forums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boot with USB drive, Clover should be loaded. Click on ‘Install Yosemite from Install Yosemite’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installation setup should appear. Use Disk Utility from Utilities and format the target drive. Create 2 partitions, for first partition where OS X will be installed, select &lt;code&gt;Mac OS Extended (Journaled)&lt;/code&gt;. Leave second partition as &lt;code&gt;Free Space&lt;/code&gt; (and Windows installation will format it properly)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proceed to Yosemite installation. Once done, it will reboot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boot again using the USB and boot into Clover. Click on ‘Install Yosemite from Install Yosemite’ to complete the installation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Post installation and setup of Clover:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I have covered installation of Yosemite. Now post installation, we will install Clover and all required kexts. At the end of this section Yosemite will be ready to use and kicking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boot with USB drive, into Clover Menu. Select &lt;code&gt;Yosemite&lt;/code&gt;(or whatever name you gave), to boot into freshly installed Yosemite&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install Clover into the EFI partition of the HDD by targeting the &lt;code&gt;Yosemite&lt;/code&gt; partition (or whatever you called it) and customize by selecting &lt;code&gt;Install Clover in the ESP&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Bootloader&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Install boot0ss in MBR&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;CloverEFI&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;CloverEFI 64-bits SATA&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Drivers64UEFI&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;EmuVariableUefi-64&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Install RC Scripts on target volume&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Install Clover Preference Pane&lt;/code&gt;. Perform installation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Yosemite drive" src="http://i.imgur.com/3nLmQKE.png" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="ESP, boot0ss" src="http://i.imgur.com/9g6ZuVM.png" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="drivers etc" src="http://i.imgur.com/KKUFAqa.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once clover is installed, EFI partition will be mounted automatically. Open it and now you need put few more files. You will need &lt;code&gt;config.plist&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;DSDT.aml&lt;/code&gt; which are specific to your system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put &lt;code&gt;config.plist&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER&lt;/code&gt; directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put &lt;code&gt;DSDT.aml&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/ACPI/patched&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put &lt;code&gt;HFSPlus.efi&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/drivers64&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/drivers64UEFI&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete &lt;code&gt;VBoxHfs-64.efi&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/drivers64&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/drivers64UEFI&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put &lt;code&gt;FakeSMC.kext&lt;/code&gt; and other kexts required in &lt;code&gt;EFI/CLOVER/kexts/10.10&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installation of Windows 8:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boot into your machine with HDD's Clover and select &lt;code&gt;Boot UEFI external from WIN81&lt;/code&gt;, hit spacebar, select and enter &lt;code&gt;Run bootx64.efi&lt;/code&gt;. It should load into Windows installation. (&lt;em&gt;image credits: fusion71au&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="clover bootmenu" src="http://i.imgur.com/essjmDT.png" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="boot windows 8" src="http://i.imgur.com/Ja4W7c1.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proceed Windows installation and complete it. Now you have Windows 8 UEFI on a Legacy BIOS!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Extras/Troubleshooting (Optional):&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you want to mount EFI partition manually. There are two ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are paranoid using Terminal, download Clover Configurator. It will ask to mount EFI partition when you open it. And you can also mount manually, see the sidebar at left side, under Tools, Mount EFI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By default, all partitions are not visible in Disk Utility. If you enable Debug Menu, you get an option to show all partitions. To enable, run the following in Terminal:&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;defaults write com.apple.DiskUtility DUDebugMenuEnabled 1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you should see an extra Debug Menu in the Disk Utility:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="debug menu" src="http://i.imgur.com/emmNXYn.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Windows ISO size is more than 4GB, then most probably &lt;code&gt;/source/install.wim&lt;/code&gt; size will be more than 4GB and copying it to FAT partition will fail. For this we have to split this file. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boot into Windows 8, create a new directory called &lt;code&gt;wim&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;C:\&lt;/code&gt; drive. Copy &lt;code&gt;install.wim&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;C:\wim&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open command prompt in admin mode and run following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt; Dism /Split-Image /ImageFile:c:\wim\install.wim /SWMFile:c:\wim\install.swm /FileSize:3500
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now see two files in &lt;code&gt;C:\wim&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replace &lt;code&gt;install.wim&lt;/code&gt; by these two files. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you can copy Windows installation ISO files to FAT partition of the USB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you want to install Windows, in Clover menu, if nothing happens when you click on Windows Installation in clover, then you have to copy &lt;code&gt;bootmgfw.efi&lt;/code&gt; into &lt;code&gt;WIN81/efi/microsoft/boot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use 7-zip in Windows, open &lt;code&gt;install.wim&lt;/code&gt; navigate to &lt;code&gt;sources/install.wim/1/Windows/Boot/EFI/bootmgfw.efi&lt;/code&gt; and extract &lt;code&gt;bootmgfw.efi&lt;/code&gt; (you don't need to extract this big ass file)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rename &lt;code&gt;cdboot.efi&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;WIN81/efi/microsoft/boot&lt;/code&gt; directory to &lt;code&gt;cdboot.BAK&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy &lt;code&gt;bootmgfw.efi&lt;/code&gt; into &lt;code&gt;WIN81/efi/microsoft/boot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now boot again with this drive. This time select &lt;code&gt;Run bootmgfw.efi&lt;/code&gt; in options (as opposed to &lt;code&gt;Run bootx64.efi&lt;/code&gt;), now it should boot fine into Windows 8 installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even after following above advice, still Windows installation gives some error, then prepare Windows 8 installation media on a separate USB drive using Rufus. You can find instructions &lt;a href="http://www.eightforums.com/tutorials/15458-uefi-bootable-usb-flash-drive-create-windows.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Use this USB drive instead and perform installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Clover installations, you do NOT need to install &lt;code&gt;Drivers64UEFI&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;EmuVariableUefi-64&lt;/code&gt;, it's not necessary for legacy BIOS. However my setup wouldn't work without it and I have no idea why. Since it does not affect the installation, I have included it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of &lt;code&gt;CloverEFI 64-bits SATA&lt;/code&gt;, you could try installing &lt;code&gt;CloverEFI 64-bits BiosBlockIO&lt;/code&gt; to speed up boot. However it may not work on few machines. So make sure you have test USB drive handy (first section of this tutorial).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disk partitioning guides: How to convert a Hybrid MBR drive to GPT and How to Convert MBR Windows to UEFI Windows Without Reinstalling - &lt;a href="http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/topic/298027-guide-aio-guides-for-hackintosh/page-18#entry2098111"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sources:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Following posts immensely helped me and you should probably read them if you want to learn more: &lt;a href="http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/topic/303149-os-x-installation-on-separate-hdd-and-windows-on-another/"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/topic/190780-guide-making-a-dsdtaml-for-dell-xps-m1330-xps-m1530-and-xps-m1730/page-81#entry1977838"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/topic/190780-guide-making-a-dsdtaml-for-dell-xps-m1330-xps-m1530-and-xps-m1730/page-81#entry1978003"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/topic/190780-guide-making-a-dsdtaml-for-dell-xps-m1330-xps-m1530-and-xps-m1730/page-81#entry1979105"&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/topic/293574-beginners-guide-to-uefi-tripledual-boot-os-x-windows-and-linux-kali-on-an-single-true-gpt-ssd/page-4#entry1992190"&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/topic/293574-beginners-guide-to-uefi-tripledual-boot-os-x-windows-and-linux-kali-on-an-single-true-gpt-ssd/page-4#entry1992190"&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why GPT/UEFI? &lt;a href="http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/topic/298027-guide-aio-guides-for-hackintosh/page-18#entry2097821"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://wiki.manjaro.org/index.php?title=Some_basics_of_MBR_v/s_GPT_and_BIOS_v/s_UEFI#MBR_vs._GPT"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unified_Extensible_Firmware_Interface#Advantages"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/dn336946.aspx"&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BiosBlockIO to speedup! - &lt;a href="http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/topic/284656-clover-general-discussion/page-239#entry2033327"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://clover-wiki.zetam.org/Installation#Using-the-installer"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://clover-wiki.zetam.org/Home"&gt;Clover Wiki&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/topic/282787-clover-v2-instructions/"&gt;Clover Instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/topic/295549-clover-config/"&gt;Sample Configurations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><category term="hackintosh"></category><category term="OSX"></category><category term="UEFI"></category></entry><entry><title>Scraping Javascript page using Python</title><link href="http://avi.im/blag/2014/scraping-javascript-website-python/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-10-18T14:03:00+05:30</updated><author><name>avi</name></author><id>tag:avi.im,2014-10-18:blag/2014/scraping-javascript-website-python/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Python library &lt;a href="https://github.com/niklasb/dryscrape"&gt;dryscape&lt;/a&gt; can be used to scrape javascript driven websites. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Code&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give an example, I created a sample page with following HTML code. (on &lt;a href="http://jsbin.com/nusefalebi"&gt;jsbin&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;charset=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Javascript scraping test&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;p&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;id=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;intro-text&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;No javascript support&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
     &lt;span class="nb"&gt;document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;getElementById&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;intro-text&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;innerHTML&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;Yay! Supports javascript&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;without javascript it says: &lt;code&gt;No javascript support&lt;/code&gt; and with javascript: &lt;code&gt;Yay! Supports javascript&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Scraping without JS support:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;requests&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;bs4&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;BeautifulSoup&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;response&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;requests&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;my_url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;soup&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;BeautifulSoup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;response&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;soup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;find&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;intro-text&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;p&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;intro-text&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;No&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;javascript&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;support&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Scraping with JS support:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;dryscrape&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;bs4&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;BeautifulSoup&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;session&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;dryscrape&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Session&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;session&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;visit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;my_url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;response&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;session&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;soup&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;BeautifulSoup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;response&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;soup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;find&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;intro-text&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;p&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;intro-text&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Yay&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;!&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Supports&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;javascript&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="scraping"></category></entry><entry><title>Installing Transmission (remote and CLI) client on Raspberry Pi</title><link href="http://avi.im/blag/2013/installing-transmission-raspberry-pi/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-09-02T19:30:00+05:30</updated><author><name>avi</name></author><id>tag:avi.im,2013-12-05:blag/2013/installing-transmission-raspberry-pi/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have found &lt;a href="http://www.transmissionbt.com/"&gt;Transmission&lt;/a&gt; to be best client to run on Raspberry Pi. In this tutorial I will explain how to install Transmission and access it using it's web interface over browser. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though this tutorial is for Raspberry Pi, it should work for any computer running Debian flavour. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First run these commands to update and upgrade the packages you have installed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get upgrade
sudo apt-get install transmission-daemon
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Create a directory where you will be saving the downloads. I have always connected a HDD to Pi and that's where all my downloads go. Fix the path accordingly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;mkdir /media/my_passport/downloads
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Run the following commands which grants access to the download directory and also adds current user to &lt;code&gt;transmission-daeomon&lt;/code&gt; group:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo chown debian-transmission:debian-transmission /media/my_passport/downloads
sudo usermod -a -G debian-transmission &amp;lt;user&amp;gt;
sudo chmod 770 /media/my_passport/downloads
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Before making any changes, make sure you are stopping the Transmission client. The config file resides at &lt;code&gt;/etc/transmission-daemon/settings.json&lt;/code&gt;. Make changes to it as per your requirements. To make some changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo service transmission-daemon stop
sudo nano /etc/transmission-daemon/settings.json
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Above should show you Nano editor, where you can edit the config file. Once done, press &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + O&lt;/code&gt; (Control plus Oh) to save and &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + X&lt;/code&gt; to exit Nano editor. Some of the changes I make are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&amp;quot;download-dir&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;/media/my_passport/downloads&amp;quot;,
...
...
&amp;quot;rpc-authentication-required&amp;quot;: true,
&amp;quot;rpc-bind-address&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;0.0.0.0&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;rpc-enabled&amp;quot;: true,
&amp;quot;rpc-password&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;password&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;rpc-port&amp;quot;: 9091,
&amp;quot;rpc-url&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;/transmission/&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;rpc-username&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;avi&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;rpc-whitelist&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;127.0.0.1, 192.168.*.*&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;rpc-whitelist-enabled&amp;quot;: false,
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Make sure you keep a strong password and the file is valid json. Or else Transmission client won't start. You can check the validity of json file on &lt;a href="http://jsonlint.com/"&gt;JSON Lint&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to start/stop/restart Transmission client:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to start:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo service transmission-daemon start
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to stop:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo service transmission-daemon stop
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to restart:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo service transmission-daemon restart
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to access Transmission in Web Browser:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transmission web client starts on port 9091 by default. Check:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;http://&amp;lt;raspberry_pi_ip_address&amp;gt;:9091
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="raspberry-pi"></category><category term="transmission"></category></entry></feed>