<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blag</title><link href="http://avi.im/blag/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://avi.im/blag/feeds/tag/hacking.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://avi.im/blag/</id><updated>2015-05-31T18:30:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>An exploit on Gaana.com gave me access to their entire User Database</title><link href="http://avi.im/blag/2015/hacking-gaana/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-31T18:30:00+05:30</updated><author><name>avi</name></author><id>tag:avi.im,2015-05-31:blag/2015/hacking-gaana/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever since &lt;a href="http://blog.mclov.in/path-uploads-your-entire-iphone-address-book-to-its-servers-22HGO5EiLJKhWZPKdMOgdw"&gt;Path - iPhone Address Book fiasco&lt;/a&gt; I have developed a habit of doing MITM and checking app's internal APIs. Yesterday I was playing around with &lt;a href="http://gaana.com"&gt;Gaana.com&lt;/a&gt;'s &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/gaana-unlimited-bollywood/id585270521?mt=8"&gt;app&lt;/a&gt;, I came across this vulnerability. Gaana was started by The Times Group, the same guys behind the national daily newspaper The Times Of India. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came across an internal API which gave me access to their entire user database (more than 11 Million records). Surprisingly, it did not require any cookies, authentication, session id or anything. Anyone with an URL would have had access to Gaana's User DB. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got access to following data of each user:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Profile picture &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email address &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date of birth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last song they listened on Gaana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="all the poor users" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/all-users-censored.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following image shows my personal info on Gaana.com which was accessible to anyone:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="this is me" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/me.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, here's &lt;a href="https://archive.is/HEvUv"&gt;proof&lt;/a&gt;. If &lt;s&gt;Archive Today&lt;/s&gt; &lt;a href="http://archive.is"&gt;Archive Is&lt;/a&gt; can access the data then anyone can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Times Internet CEO Satyan Gajwani's user id on Gaana user database is &lt;code&gt;72&lt;/code&gt; and the last song he listened on Gaana was &lt;em&gt;Happy Birthday&lt;/em&gt; from album &lt;em&gt;Party Time Songs And Nursery Rhymes&lt;/em&gt;. The current Gaana's business head, Pawan Agarwal's user id is &lt;code&gt;831&lt;/code&gt; and the last song he listened on Gaana was &lt;em&gt;Hangover&lt;/em&gt; from movie &lt;em&gt;Kick&lt;/em&gt;. Avinash Mudaliar, the co-founder and former head of Gaana's user id is &lt;code&gt;57&lt;/code&gt;. And The last song he listened on Gaana was &lt;em&gt;Khuda Bhi&lt;/em&gt; from movie &lt;em&gt;Ek Paheli Leela&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I had access to the all the users of Gaana. &lt;strong&gt;Before I got bored, the last record I checked was 11,872,026 (11 Million something) user&lt;/strong&gt;. However not all of data was filled, some profiles were deleted and some had null values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got an idea about how they are handling user account deletion. Spoiler alert, even if they have deleted your account, they still retain your profile picture. However I have no idea how do I delete my account. I couldn't find any such option in the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Hack&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During normal session, I came across an API which was retrieving user data from Gaana's database:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;api.gaana.com/user.php?type=get_user_object&amp;amp;&amp;amp;user_id=&amp;lt;user_id&amp;gt;&amp;amp;token=&amp;lt;token&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;above API requires &lt;code&gt;user_id&lt;/code&gt; of the user whose data needs to be accessed and an authentication &lt;code&gt;token&lt;/code&gt; for this transaction. Now in a well designed app, the user should be able make requests only to his account and not to anyone else's. The token, may be, should linked to the user id, generated every time and should authenticate the request. The unique token per session should give access to the unique user. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The API call to get my info was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;http://api.gaana.com/user.php?type=get_user_object&amp;amp;&amp;amp;user_id=11875135&amp;amp;token=d4f9763714ad89e839605e460ef1b4556
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;My first doubt was, why there is even a &lt;code&gt;user_id&lt;/code&gt; field. I am not an expert developer, but if I were designing I wouldn't include &lt;code&gt;user_id&lt;/code&gt; in the API call. The &lt;code&gt;token&lt;/code&gt; should be just enough. And I would regenerate it for every session or make it expire after few hours or something like that. Or I would use OAuth2. And of course, make this communication over TLS/SSL. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I copied the above URL and opened it in Browser and it showed my info. Without HTTPS. I have never used or logged into Gaana.com in my browser. So I assumed it's not doing any other validation and using only &lt;code&gt;token&lt;/code&gt;. Though not using HTTPS was worrisome. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I incremented my &lt;code&gt;user_id&lt;/code&gt; by 1 and sent GET again. Return response status was 200. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to be really sure. So I created a throwaway profile on Gaana. And yes, &lt;a href="https://archive.is/bkuNY"&gt;I was able to access it with same token&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I kept on changing &lt;code&gt;user_id&lt;/code&gt; and started sending GETs. It always worked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="user1" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/user1.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User 9,99,999:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="user999999" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/user999999.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User 11872026(11 Million something):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="user11872026" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/user11872026.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several hours had already passed, but still my token was active. I logged out of Gaana app, cleared app data, but it was still working. Then I thought, would it work if I change the token? &lt;a href="https://archive.is/lTAIx"&gt;Entered&lt;/a&gt; some gibberish of same length:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="somerandomtoken" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/somerandomtoken.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well yeah, it did work. Then another &lt;a href="https://archive.is/wsGC6"&gt;try&lt;/a&gt;, you know, just to be sure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="somerandomtoken2" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/somerandomtoken2.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm...There's something &lt;a href="https://archive.is/BngCd"&gt;really fishy&lt;/a&gt; was going on. What if I don't provide any &lt;code&gt;token&lt;/code&gt; at all? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="wut" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/wut.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WUT!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So token wasn't required at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All you had to was loop through &lt;code&gt;user_id&lt;/code&gt; starting from 1. Following simple four line Python script was enough to fetch all the details of Gaana users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;requests&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;api&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;http://api.gaana.com/user.php?type=get_user_object&amp;amp;&amp;amp;user_id={0}&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;SOME_NUM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;requests&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;api&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;format&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;())&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It took me ~50 minutes (used &lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/time.html#time.time"&gt;&lt;code&gt;time.time()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) to fetch 10,000 user records:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="frequency" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/frequency.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bonus:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following image shows how user deletion is being done on Gaana. Note that the profile picture was valid, so I guess they retain your profile picture even if you delete your account from Gaana. However I have no idea how to delete my account on Gaana. Most probably, I have to contact them to have my account deleted. (which I should do very very soon.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="a deleted user" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/deleteduser.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A random row with null data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="a null user" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/nulluser.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Script&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Removed the script on request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Aftermath&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the entire chain of events:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the exploit on 12/May/2015, ~3.30 PM. By 4.30 PM, I was convinced that Gaana had a vulnerability. I Googled for their security team email, searched if they have Bug Bounty Programmes. But neither I found any email or Bug Bounty programmes on Gaana. Gaana did not have any 'Contact Us' in their website footer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tweeted them on Twitter and waited for response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gaana"&gt;@gaana&lt;/a&gt; lets say hypothetically some1 hacked ur server &amp;amp; got access. Hw should they go abut contacting ur security team? security@gaana.com?&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; avi (@iavins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/iavins/status/598088551394189312"&gt;May 12, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="http://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were active on Twitter, replying to others. But did not reply to me. May be they thought I was pulling some prank. Also, I did find a contact form on their website after bit of searching(to which they responded after three days).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tweeted again in night:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gaana"&gt;@gaana&lt;/a&gt; guys, can you tell me how do I get in touch with your security/bugs team?&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; avi (@iavins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/iavins/status/598166155736457216"&gt;May 12, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they finally replied to me next day and asked me to DM, which &lt;a href="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/dm.png"&gt;I did&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally someone from Gaana emailed me on May 13th evening and I sent him all the details, including SQL dump (so that he takes me seriously).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 17th (i.e. 5 days after the exploit), I emailed them again asking why it wasn't fixed yet. Their site was up and running, but exploit wasn't fixed. I was worried if someone else figures this out and makes the data public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaana called me again and assured me that it will be fixed soon and it's taking time because of API backward compatibility issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometime on May 23-24rd (i.e. ~10 days after exploit) the vulnerability was partially fixed. Now you were able to get full name and profile pic. However API was still openly accessible, over HTTP, in the browser:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="partial fix" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/partialfix.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 28th May, &lt;a href="http://www.thegeekbyte.com/4841/gaana-com-database-compromised-by-hackers/"&gt;MakMan and g00n&lt;/a&gt; found another exploit using SQL injection. And Gaana was down for maintenance for most of the day. In evening, I received a call from Gaana and was assured that it will be fixed asap. I was hoping they will fix it, as it's been already two weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I was wrong. It wasn't &lt;a href="https://archive.is/uuifC"&gt;fixed&lt;/a&gt; and I sent another email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 30 2015, evening &lt;a href="https://archive.is/7EaEx"&gt;Gaana&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/gaanadown.png"&gt;was down&lt;/a&gt; again, so was the &lt;a href="https://archive.is/ksPRd"&gt;API end point&lt;/a&gt;. Are they finally fixing the exploit I found? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="api end was down" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/apidown.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 30, 2015, around ~10pm, I checked again. The exploit was finally &lt;a href="https://archive.is/fWEDq"&gt;fixed&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="partial fix" src="http://avi.im/blag/images/2015/hacking-gaana/apifixed.png" width="99%" height="99%" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaana team took almost 3 weeks to fix the exploit. Would they have treated this exploit differently, if I had made this public since day one? Also, it was not easy for me to reach out to Gaana and it took them a day to reply. It was difficult to find their contact information from their site, I wonder do they even have security team for handling exploits. Usually companies have emails like security@company.com for such things. Gaana mentions no such things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not like Gaana is a new kid in the block, it was launched in 2010 by &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Times_Internet"&gt;Times Internet&lt;/a&gt;, who run the largest websites of India - Times of India, The Economic Times, Indiatimes etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, Gaana is not an exception. A cursory search on Indian companies will tell you that, hardly any companies have such policies. Recent vulnerabilities found on Ola, Freecharge, Zopnow, FoodPanda etc make me more sceptical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions to ponder: Is our private data really safe with Indian startups? Are web/app security practices completely being ignored, to win the race of 'first to be in the market'? Do companies really care about privacy of their users? or only about profits?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="hacking"></category><category term="python"></category></entry></feed>